JORDAN GLESENER

900 State ST • Salem, OR 97301 | (206)-604-7763 | jordan.glesener@gmail.com

Summary of Qualifications

Data Scientist who has a Computer Science background. Uses Computer Science background to help break down big problems into smaller parts and demonstrate an ability to operate as an individual within a system. Fast learner: Finished college in 3 years with 2 Bachelors and a Masters and learned 6 computing languages.

- Scripting, Programming: R, Python, Java, C, HTML, Unreal Engine Blueprint, JavaScript
- Full Stack Web Development with PHP, HTML, and CSS
- Project Planning and Publishing: Github, Rmd
- Data Engineering and Visualization with SQL and Power BI
- Cloud Computing with Azure/GCP
- Machine Learning in Python Data Stack

Expected Graduation Aug 2024

Data Architecture and Pipeline Design

Education

Master of Data Science

Willamette University - Salem, OR

BA in Computer Science, Data Science

Willamette University - Salem, OR GPA 3.67

Relevant Coursework: Models and Machine Learning, Data Engineering with SQL, Cloud Computing, Power BI, Data Visualization and Analysis with R

Relevant Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

Mar 2024 - Apr 2024

Atkinson School of Management - Willamette University | Salem, Oregon

- Copyedited a research paper regarding the value of web programming over Python in a business and accounting context.
- Provided useful insight to a business school professor on pedagogical tools for programming.

Software Development Intern

Jun 2023 - Aug 2023

Willamette University - Athletics Department - Football Team | Salem, Oregon

- Created an app that allows coaches to visualize plays in the playbook in a 3d space that was
 used in practice to help substantially improve practice efficiency.
- Worked with coaches to help translate their vision of an ideal application into a practical app.

Projects

Football Team Management Web App

Feb 2024 - May 2024

Feb 2024 - May 2024

JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, CSS

 Used PHP and SQL to create a dynamic interface where users could create plays, playbooks, and invite new players to their team. Used Bootstrap Framework for an aesthetic frontend.

Housing Data Pipeline and Dashboard

PostgreSQL, PowerBI, Docker

 Used Railway to run a Docker container that scraped data from an housing api on a schedule, cleaned the data, and output into a Power BI Dashboard that displayed the data in a consumable way.